Martin Kemp

- Birmingham
- martin@foxandducksoftware.co.uk
- 07975512398
- https://martinke.mp

SUMMARY

I consider myself a fast learner and quick to adapt to new challenges, I always strive to work with the latest technology and with open source software.

-What I've worked on – I've worked on many different projects, large payment and financial systems, I've recently worked as a Build/Release Engineer and have implemented systems to improve the build and release processes of businesses.

-Side Projects- I'm the current maintainer of the cmder project http://cmder.net I've founded my own company Fox and Duck Software Ltd. which I currently use to contract with.

-I'm really good at- Automation, DevOps and Build/Release Engineering.

SKILLS

- Microsoft SQL Server
- Software Development
- Teamwork
- Technical Support
- .NET
- WPF
- Flask
- DevOps
- Bash
- System Administration
- Agile Methodologies
- Jenkins
- Virtualization
- Enterprise Software
- SSIS
- WinForms
- Database Administration
- Reporting & Analysis
- ASP.NET
- Visual Studio
- Windows
- XML
- Management
- Cloud Computing
- Amazon Web Services (AWS)

- Windows 7
- Web Development
- JavaScript
- C# 4.0
- HTML 5
- Python
- Git
- Unix Shell Scripting
- GNU/Linux
- Debian
- Continuous Integration
- REST
- VMware ESX
- SSRS
- Github
- Application Support
- CSS3
- IIS
- Testing
- Web Applications
- SQL
- HTML
- Windows Server
- Shell Scripting
- OS X

EXPERIENCE

PixelWarp Limited

Chief Technology Officer

Virtual Reality Software Specialists.

06 / 2015 - Present

Founder

Software Development - Automation, Build Systems, Mobile applications.

Intellectual Property Office

10 / 2015 - 03 / 2016

Contract Build Engineer

Contracted in as a SME in regards to Build/Release Engineering, DevOps processes, and to provide novel solutions to the issues that the current release team was experiencing. Involved with multiple projects the improve the speed and efficiency of the release team and strived to reduce workload and unnecessary bureaucracy.

Encouraged the use of the Git DVCS with Gitlab and the general use of open source software within the team.

Technologies and Tools used: GNU/Linux Jenkins CI XLRelease Nagios Gitlab Batch/Powershell/bash scripting Groovy SVN & Git HTML5 & Javascript (JQuery) ASP.NET 5 Docker Puppet VMWare

Inspired Gaming Group

10 / 2014 - 09 / 2015

Build Engineer

Creating and supporting the Inspired Gaming Group build system using my skills in software engineering and GNU/Linux system administration and promoting DevOps methodology within the business.

Responsibilities include: - Support and administrate GNU/Linux Servers. - Create and develop novel solutions for the businesses automation needs. - Work with developers to improve their quality of life when working on new or existing games. - Promote test driven development

Technologies and Tools used: GNU/Linux Python Flask Web Framework Jenkins CI Batch/Powershell/bash scripting Groovy SVN & Git HTML5 & Javascript (JQuery)

Police Mutual

03 / 2013 - 10 / 2014

Application Support

During my time at Police Mutual I have supported the running of the main financial system within the company, this included changes to data when needed, supported testing and training of new features for this system.

I have opted to assist first line support when they have low numbers and support users with my knowledge of Windows operating systems.

I have been involved with having a better IT presence within the company, being around the users when they have issues and supporting their work and with weekly and fortnightly meetings with heads of individual teams to note issues that require work.

I have assisted the development team by fixing bugs within the system of which they have no time to look at, this included an issue which prevented multiple customers from purchasing popular products.

I am currently working on an additional system that will automate many data fixes that are usually done manually, this will significantly reduce the workload of IT in general.

I was (from Nov 2013) representing the IT department as their VOICE representative. The VOICE represents the entire workforce and is a team with which the Group will: - Share information about strategic decisions and issues of importance to staff - Promote an exchange of views about those issues - Test ideas and approaches with staff - Give staff an opportunity to influence the implementation of decisions

Over the course of five months, I have represented the views of the IT department over contract changes and made sure their voices and concerns were heard during this process.

Technologies Used:

Microsoft SQL (T-SQL) .NET Framework 4.0+ ASP.NET Window Forms Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) IIS SSIS SSRS System Centre Service Manager

Compass Group

09 / 2012 - 11 / 2012

Support Analyst

Help end users solve issues they are currently having with PCs, POS devices and network devices to ensure they can continue working.

Capgemini

09 / 2011 - 08 / 2012

Junior Developer

Developed in a small team a consolidated database/web front end to all personnel management within the company, using technologies such as ASP.NET, C#, MSSQL, SSRS, SSIS

Also developed and debugged a contract management system for the DfE within a medium sized team.

Zenos IT Training

02/2011 - 07/2011

Apprentice

Gained knowledge about Desktop support and gained many qualifications such as my A+, MCITP MCSA and MCSE qualifications.

EDUCATION

Zenos IT Academy

CompTIA A+

2011 - 2011

05 / 2011 - 08 / 2014

Advanced Apprenticeship Level 3 Diploma , IT & Telecoms Professionals

INTERESTS

New Technology, GNU/Linux Administration, Small Development Projects including working with Raspberry Pi and VPSs.

CERTIFICATIONS

MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional	07 / 2011
Microsoft	
MCSA: Windows 7	04 / 2012
Microsoft	
MCITP: Enterprise Desktop Support Technician on Windows 7	07 / 2011
Microsoft	
MCTS: Windows 7, Configuration	07 / 2011
Microsoft	
MTA: Windows Server Administration Fundamentals	07 / 2011
Microsoft	
MTA: Windows Operating System Fundamentals	07 / 2011
Microsoft	
MTA: Networking Fundamentals	05 / 2011
Microsoft	

Duolingo German Fluency: Beginner (Estimated)

Duolingo

LANGUAGES

• English (Native or bilingual proficiency)

• German (Elementary proficiency)

01 / 2016